<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>mathematics on A fractal spectrum of tales</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/tags/mathematics/</link><description>Recent content in mathematics on A fractal spectrum of tales</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 09:30:42 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.mseri.me/tags/mathematics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Micro Course on Sub-Riemannian Geometry</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/micro-course-on-sr-geometry/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 09:30:42 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.mseri.me/micro-course-on-sr-geometry/</guid><description>Last year I had the opportunity to give the first talk at the The Dutch Differential Topology &amp;amp; Geometry seminar (DDT&amp;amp;G). This was a 3 hour long event in which I had the chance to give a high-level introduction to sub-Riemannian geometry and present some interesting results and open questions partly related to my research.
In the first part of the seminar I introduced what are sub-Riemannian structures, where do they come from and what are some of the major properties and open questions, using some famous examples to drive the discussion.</description></item><item><title>Material from Hamiltonian Mechanics 2021</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/links-from-hm/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 00:15:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.mseri.me/links-from-hm/</guid><description>During the current incarnation of the course in Hamiltonian Mechanics I have collected some amount of material to share with the students. To avoid losing it in the guts of our teaching CMS, I leave it here for posterity, practically copy-pasting it without edits because I am really tired :D
The books on SpringerLinks linked below are accessible from our students for free via the university proxy but in general (unfortunately) not open access.</description></item><item><title>Lecture notes on Analysis on Manifolds</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/analysis-on-manifolds/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 13:17:25 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.mseri.me/analysis-on-manifolds/</guid><description>In the previous academic term I had the pleasure to teach Analysis on Manifolds, essentially an introduction to differential geometry for third year students.
In the course I tried to address the topic with the perspective that some of the students would be joining also my master course in Hamiltonian Mechanics later on next year. So many of the topics go in the direction of introducing the prerequisites for studying flows, symplectic geometry and sub-Riemannian geometry.</description></item><item><title>Micro Course in Spectral Sub Riemannian Geometry</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/micro-course-ddtandg/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 22:38:21 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.mseri.me/micro-course-ddtandg/</guid><description>Recently, I have had the pleasure and honour to give a &amp;ldquo;micro&amp;rdquo; course on spectral sub-Riemannian geometry for the Dutch Differential Topology and Geometry seminar. Given the current global circumstances, the course was given via Zoom and the organizers and participants have been kind enough to have it recorded and published online.
You can access the recordings of the first and second lecture on the YouTube Channel of the DDT&amp;amp;G. The slides are also available (beware, they are 99Mb of handwritten pdf!</description></item><item><title>Lecture notes on Hamiltonian mechanics (update)</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/hamiltonian-mechanics-ams/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 22:00:21 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.mseri.me/hamiltonian-mechanics-ams/</guid><description>I have just released a small update to the Hamiltonian Mechanics lecture notes here. This contains some edits to improve the english and fix a few typos. The lecture notes have also been approved to appear in the AMS Open Math Notes, which seems to be a very nice initiative, full of very interesting and high quality content.</description></item><item><title>Lecture notes on Hamiltonian mechanics</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/lecture-notes-hamiltonian-mechanics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 15:20:19 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.mseri.me/lecture-notes-hamiltonian-mechanics/</guid><description>In the last academic term, I had the great pleasure to teach Hamiltonian Mechanics, an optional master course for mathematics and physics students. Even though the course was based on Arnold&amp;rsquo;s beautiful book, my plan for the course was to give a panoramic on the modern theory of integrable systems and perturbation theory. Of course, my grand plan, was way to optimistic. And between the time available, a bad flu and then the pandemic landing, we were able to do much less than what I hoped for.</description></item><item><title>On teaching mathematics - By V. I. Arnold</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/on-teaching-mathematics/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2015 01:11:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.mseri.me/on-teaching-mathematics/</guid><description>This is an extended text of the address at the discussion on teaching of mathematics in Palais de Découverte in Paris on 7 March 1997.
Mathematics is a part of physics. Physics is an experimental science, a part of natural science. Mathematics is the part of physics where experiments are cheap.
The Jacobi identity (which forces the heights of a triangle to cross at one point) is an experimental fact in the same way as that the Earth is round (that is, homeomorphic to a ball).</description></item><item><title>On the differential logistic equation</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/thought-on-the-differential-logistic-equation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2013 14:15:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.mseri.me/thought-on-the-differential-logistic-equation/</guid><description>This fall I am teaching Mathematical Methods for Scientist. This week we started to talk about differential equations and for the lecture I was looking for an example of a broadely used first order ODE: my final choice has been the logistic equation.
It is a fairly simple differential equation that is used to describe the growth (and saturation) of populations in environments with competition for limited resources. Before entering into more details I think it&amp;rsquo;s time to digress slightly and talk about something simpler.</description></item><item><title>The beauty of mathematics</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/the-beauty-of-mathematics/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2013 19:36:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.mseri.me/the-beauty-of-mathematics/</guid><description>After having watched this video I hope you will agree with Bertrand Russell:
&amp;quot;Mathematics, rightly viewed, possesses not only truth, but supreme beauty — a beauty cold and austere, without the gorgeous trappings of painting or music.&amp;quot;
— Bertrand Russell
And this is just a scratch of the surface of the mysterious wonderful world that is hiding behind those fascinating symbols.
A video by Yann Pineill &amp;amp; Nicolas Lefaucheux.</description></item></channel></rss>