<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Homebrew on A fractal spectrum of tales</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/tags/homebrew/</link><description>Recent content in Homebrew on A fractal spectrum of tales</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 10:40:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.mseri.me/tags/homebrew/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fix Hombrew on OS X Yosemite</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/fix-hombrew-on-os-x-yosemite/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2014 15:58:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.mseri.me/fix-hombrew-on-os-x-yosemite/</guid><description>&lt;p>If for some reasons you&amp;rsquo;ve been crazy enough to install the first developer beta of Mac OSX 10.01 Yosemite, you&amp;rsquo;ve probably noticed that &lt;a href="https://brew.sh/">Homebrew&lt;/a> stopped working.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One possible fix is to delete homebrew and reinstall everything but I am too lazy and too attached to my list of installed packages to accept it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first error I&amp;rsquo;ve got while running &lt;code>brew update&lt;/code> was related to &lt;em>missing system ruby 1.8&lt;/em>. This appears because OSX finally updated to &lt;code>ruby 2.0&lt;/code> and this conflicts with the static link saved in one of Hombrew executables.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Installing scientific python libraries on OSX</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/installing-scientific-python-libraries-on-osx/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2014 19:06:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.mseri.me/installing-scientific-python-libraries-on-osx/</guid><description>&lt;p>For a recent project, I had the necessity to install (or update) some of the scientific python libraries that I use for computation (and to avoit matlab). I was aware of &lt;a href="https://www.thisisthegreenroom.com/2011/installing-python-numpy-scipy-matplotlib-and-ipython-on-lion/">a not too recent tutorial&lt;/a> in regard that left me quit unhappy at the time, in particular I strongly disagree with their practice of changing OSX official symlinks to point at the new Python install.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Given that I am not alone in the project, I decided to write a short tutorial trying to include all the necessary steps for a successful installation of python, numpy, scipy, matplotlib, ipython and qutip.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>