<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tips on A fractal spectrum of tales</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/tags/tips/</link><description>Recent content in Tips on A fractal spectrum of tales</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2014 18:26:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.mseri.me/tags/tips/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Socks proxy with ssh</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/socks-proxy-with-ssh/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2014 18:24:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.mseri.me/socks-proxy-with-ssh/</guid><description>&lt;p>When you work in the University, it is very likely that during a trip or the weekend you urge to connect via the University to have access to Journals and other academic resources.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Often enough this requires long and complicated procedures involving the setup of rarely updated proprietary VPN softwares that sometimes like to install their obscure helpers to monitor the traffic and prevent you to open malicious websites. Helpers that would keep working in background sending to unspecified servers all your business even when the VPN is off&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fix WiFi on OS X by tweaking the MTU</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/fixing-wifi-on-os-x-by-tweaking-the-mtu/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2014 23:18:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.mseri.me/fixing-wifi-on-os-x-by-tweaking-the-mtu/</guid><description>&lt;p>After I had installed the first developer beta of Yosemite I started experiencing serious WiFi issues &lt;strong>at home&lt;/strong>, with the connection dropping after few seconds of activity. Only apparent solution was to disable and reenable periodically the wifi until it started working.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The issue was not present whene I was in my office or using public wifi&amp;rsquo;s around. And removing the network setup to have them reset to default didn&amp;rsquo;t help.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Convert djvu files to a decently small pdf</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/convert-djvu-files-to-a-decently-small-pdf/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2013 21:05:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.mseri.me/convert-djvu-files-to-a-decently-small-pdf/</guid><description>&lt;p>Despite there are few decent &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DjVu">djvu&lt;/a> readers, they are not as comfortable as the pdf readers. Moreover, it is not really possible to open djvu files in eInk ebook readers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Additionally, if you have ever tried to convert djvu files to pdf (or ps), you should have noted that the output is either corrupted or unbelievably big.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is an hack that could come in help. Open your &lt;code>.bashrc&lt;/code> (or &lt;code>.zshrc&lt;/code> if you use Zsh) and define this new &lt;a href="https://tldp.org/LDP/abs/html/aliases.html">alias&lt;/a> (i.e. add this line somewhere, say at the end of the file)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>On iTerm2 and solarized dark</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/on-iterm2-and-solarized-dark/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2013 18:45:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.mseri.me/on-iterm2-and-solarized-dark/</guid><description>&lt;p>This weekend I&amp;rsquo;ve spent some time to understand &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Z_shell">Z Shell&lt;/a>. I admit that I&amp;rsquo;ve should have done it ages ago. I actually regret not having done it ages ago, I would have saved a lot of time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Moving your &lt;code>.bashrc&lt;/code> to your new &lt;code>.zshrc&lt;/code> is almost just copy and paste. And you suddently find yourself with a shell that makes you feel in the future!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you additionally install &lt;a href="https://github.com/robbyrussell/oh-my-zsh">oh my zsh&lt;/a>, &lt;em>the only thing that your shell will be missing is the capability of making coffee&lt;/em>. The official description is literally true:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>