<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>education on A fractal spectrum of tales</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/tags/education/</link><description>Recent content in education on A fractal spectrum of tales</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 10:59:27 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.mseri.me/tags/education/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Giving Good Maths Talks</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/giving-good-maths-talks/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 10:59:27 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.mseri.me/giving-good-maths-talks/</guid><description>The upcoming block I have to coordinate a course on giving good talks. This also meant looking for good extra material for the students to reflect on what it means to give a good talk, what to be aware of and what tips can help to do a good job. Here is a collection of the resources I liked so far:
MAA has a curated list of resources on giving mathematics talks which includes plenty of examples of good mathematics presentations There is an essay by John McCarthy on how to give a good colloquium talk with a response blog post on how to give a good 20min talk On the blog of the AMS there is a nice post on preparing a conference presentation, from what it means to many resources on how it can be done What characterizes a good presentation?</description></item><item><title>Panel discussion on the Future of Higher Education</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/panel-discussion-on-the-future-of-higher-education/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 13:28:03 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.mseri.me/panel-discussion-on-the-future-of-higher-education/</guid><description>Recently I was invited to participate to a panel discussion as part of a symposium on the future of higher education hosted by our faculty for the launch of the Centre for Learning and Teaching.
I joined other four incredible panelists and we have been given in advance five quite broad (and though) questions on some important aspects of (high) education. I want report here my contribution, with some extra commentary at the end.</description></item></channel></rss>