<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>University on A fractal spectrum of tales</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/tags/university/</link><description>Recent content in University on A fractal spectrum of tales</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 09:10:59 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.mseri.me/tags/university/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Four months in the University Council</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/four-months-in-the-university-council/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 09:10:59 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.mseri.me/four-months-in-the-university-council/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This is a repost of my original blog post from the Science Faction blog: &lt;a href="https://www.rug.nl/about-ug/organization/administrative-organization/participation-decision-making/uraad/science-faction/blog/the-uc-experience-four-months-later">The UC experience, four months later&lt;/a>. Since university blog posts get archived after a while, I&amp;rsquo;m keeping this copy here for reference.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s been four months since I joined the university council, and I am still quite glad I had this opportunity. So far, it has been a continuous learning process. Not just about the university and the forces shaping it from the inside and out, but also, and maybe more importantly, about how to run large meetings with an open mind and an atmosphere that fosters lively yet respectful discussions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Our first month in the University Council</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/our-first-month-in-the-university-council/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 12:00:16 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.mseri.me/our-first-month-in-the-university-council/</guid><description>&lt;p>A month has passed since the new &lt;a href="https://www.rug.nl/about-ug/organization/administrative-organization/participation-decision-making/uraad/?lang=en">University Council (UC)&lt;/a> was installed, and I think it&amp;rsquo;s time to look back on what has happened so far, and what seems to lie ahead. When I enlisted I promised myself to help improve the transparency of the discussions and keep an open channel with anybody that could be interested.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This first month has been a whirlwind of activity, training, and initial discussions. Much of our work so far has focused on preparation: only now I start to see how crucial is to build a good foundation of knowledge and trust for the decisions and actions to come.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>