<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tutorial on A fractal spectrum of tales</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/tags/tutorial/</link><description>Recent content in Tutorial on A fractal spectrum of tales</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2015 21:09:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.mseri.me/tags/tutorial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Move to ghc 7.8.2 on MacOSX</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/move-to-ghc-7-8-2-on-macosx/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 15:17:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.mseri.me/move-to-ghc-7-8-2-on-macosx/</guid><description>Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing with some functional languages: haskell, lisp (in particular the scheme dialect, see e.g. chicken or racket) and elixir (I very much like it and I really appreciate that it runs on the erlang VM).
Each of those has something pretty unique and I believe is very worth learning. I cannot stress how much material you can find both online and in libraries to learn them (except for elixir but its website does a really good job and there will be plenty of books very soon out) and how strong thay can change your way of programming.</description></item><item><title>Installing Scientific Python 3 libraries on OSX (and julia with IJulia)</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/installing-scientific-python-3-libraries-on-osx-and-julia-with-ijulia/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2014 13:35:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.mseri.me/installing-scientific-python-3-libraries-on-osx-and-julia-with-ijulia/</guid><description>In a recent post, I tried to explain how to install scientific python libraries on OSX and get rid of the most common errors. In that case everythong I did was for python 2.7.
Yesterday I decided to fully move to python 3.4. I&amp;rsquo;ve removed my python installation via homebrew and with it all the installed packages.
Moving to python 3 is straightforward if you have done the procedure described in my previous post, it all really reduces to replace every occurrence of python in that post with python3 and every occurrence of pip with pip3.</description></item><item><title>Installing scientific python libraries on OSX</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/installing-scientific-python-libraries-on-osx/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2014 19:06:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.mseri.me/installing-scientific-python-libraries-on-osx/</guid><description>For a recent project, I had the necessity to install (or update) some of the scientific python libraries that I use for computation (and to avoit matlab). I was aware of a not too recent tutorial in regard that left me quit unhappy at the time, in particular I strongly disagree with their practice of changing OSX official symlinks to point at the new Python install.
Given that I am not alone in the project, I decided to write a short tutorial trying to include all the necessary steps for a successful installation of python, numpy, scipy, matplotlib, ipython and qutip.</description></item><item><title>Git workflow for lazy mathematicians</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/git-workflow-for-lazy-mathematicians/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2013 16:40:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.mseri.me/git-workflow-for-lazy-mathematicians/</guid><description>This post is pretty old, You can refer to my new post here for a more modern version.
First of all, what is git? Citing its website
Git is a free and open source distributed version control system designed to handle everything from small to very large projects with speed and efficiency. [It] is easy to learn and has a tiny footprint with lightning fast performance.
In other words Git provides a source control repository that enables you to roll back code changes as needed, to merge the updates when collaborating with others and eventually to have an online backup of your work.</description></item><item><title>Ghost up and running on Amazon EC2</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/ghost-up-and-running-on-amazon-ec2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2013 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.mseri.me/ghost-up-and-running-on-amazon-ec2/</guid><description>I had my free Amazon EC2 instance waiting for this moment since my last use of it.
I spent my few free hours setting up a decent (I hope) theme for Ghost, and reading around what to do and what not to do to have it up and running. My main reference was the nice blog post How to set up an Amazon EC2 instance to host ghost for free.</description></item></channel></rss>