<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Amazon EC2 on A fractal spectrum of tales</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/tags/amazon-ec2/</link><description>Recent content in Amazon EC2 on A fractal spectrum of tales</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2013 15:57:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.mseri.me/tags/amazon-ec2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ghost on Amazon EC2 without using sudo</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/ghost-on-amazon-ec2-without-using-sudo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2013 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.mseri.me/ghost-on-amazon-ec2-without-using-sudo/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking since &lt;a href="https://www.mseri.me/ghost-up-and-running-on-amazon-ec2/">yesterday&amp;rsquo;s post&lt;/a> how to run the ghost blog at the user level, wihout the need of using sudo.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="use-nginx"> &lt;a class="hanchor" href="#use-nginx">#&lt;/a>&amp;nbsp;Use Nginx
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In a production environment I would probably run ghos as a nginx subdomain (i.e. &lt;em>ghost.mseri.me&lt;/em>), eventually forwarding the domain to the same address (e.g. typing &lt;em>mseri.me&lt;/em> you would end up automatically in &lt;em>ghost.mseri.me&lt;/em>). For this purpose you either know by hearth how to do it, or you can follow one of the many tutorial available online. I think this is a very neat and effective way of proceeding.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ghost up and running on Amazon EC2</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/ghost-up-and-running-on-amazon-ec2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2013 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.mseri.me/ghost-up-and-running-on-amazon-ec2/</guid><description>&lt;p>I had my free Amazon EC2 instance waiting for this moment since &lt;a href="https://github.com/mseri/pplofthesoil">my last use of it&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I spent my few free hours setting up a decent (I hope) &lt;a href="https://github.com/mseri/purity">theme&lt;/a> for &lt;a href="https://ghost.org">Ghost&lt;/a>, and reading around what to do and what not to do to have it up and running. My main reference was the nice blog post &lt;a href="https://www.howtoinstallghost.com/how-to-setup-an-amazon-ec2-instance-to-host-ghost-for-free/">How to set up an Amazon EC2 instance to host ghost for free&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I followed more or less all the steps suggested in the guide but there was still something missing: I wanted my Ghost blog to be running even when I am not logged in the EC2 instance.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>