<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Haskell on A fractal spectrum of tales</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/tags/haskell/</link><description>Recent content in Haskell on A fractal spectrum of tales</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2014 15:24:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.mseri.me/tags/haskell/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Left pipe in Haskell</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/left-pipe-in-haskell/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2014 15:24:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.mseri.me/left-pipe-in-haskell/</guid><description>If you read this blog, you know that I am very biased by having worked with unix shells for almost two decades and that I am addicted to the use of pipes (see e.g. Piping with Swift). I really find much more natural to see data moving from left to right.
Yesterday I was thinking that in Haskell everything is an expression and that you can easily define infix operators. Thus it must be possible to implement a shell-like pipe.</description></item><item><title>Implementing Either type in Swift</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/implementing-either-type-in-swift/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2014 14:11:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.mseri.me/implementing-either-type-in-swift/</guid><description>It has been only a couple of days since Apple announced and released Swift. It has possibly been the most important and interesting announcement of Apple in the last few years and started an amount of discussions around the web.
With the hours passing, we&amp;rsquo;ve found out that there was at least another Swift in the history of programming languages (with a similar icon) and that Swift is under development since 2010 and its father is Chris Lattner, creator of clang and LLVM.</description></item><item><title>Move to ghc 7.8.2 on MacOSX</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/move-to-ghc-7-8-2-on-macosx/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 15:17:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.mseri.me/move-to-ghc-7-8-2-on-macosx/</guid><description>Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing with some functional languages: haskell, lisp (in particular the scheme dialect, see e.g. chicken or racket) and elixir (I very much like it and I really appreciate that it runs on the erlang VM).
Each of those has something pretty unique and I believe is very worth learning. I cannot stress how much material you can find both online and in libraries to learn them (except for elixir but its website does a really good job and there will be plenty of books very soon out) and how strong thay can change your way of programming.</description></item></channel></rss>