<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Git on A fractal spectrum of tales</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/tags/git/</link><description>Recent content in Git on A fractal spectrum of tales</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 14:56:34 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.mseri.me/tags/git/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A brief introduction to git, with an eye towards mathematicians</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/a-brief-intro-to-git/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 14:56:34 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.mseri.me/a-brief-intro-to-git/</guid><description>This is a followup to my previous post on git from 11 years ago. I&amp;rsquo;ve been using git for a while now and I&amp;rsquo;ve learned a few things since then, that I think are worth sharing.
I am not going to explain in detail what git is, how to install it and how it works; there are plenty of resources for that. It will be enough for our purposes to know that git is a version control system that allows you to keep track of changes in your files and collaborate with others.</description></item><item><title>Git workflow for lazy mathematicians</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/git-workflow-for-lazy-mathematicians/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2013 16:40:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.mseri.me/git-workflow-for-lazy-mathematicians/</guid><description>This post is pretty old, You can refer to my new post here for a more modern version.
First of all, what is git? Citing its website
Git is a free and open source distributed version control system designed to handle everything from small to very large projects with speed and efficiency. [It] is easy to learn and has a tiny footprint with lightning fast performance.
In other words Git provides a source control repository that enables you to roll back code changes as needed, to merge the updates when collaborating with others and eventually to have an online backup of your work.</description></item></channel></rss>