<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>blog on A fractal spectrum of tales</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/tags/blog/</link><description>Recent content in blog on A fractal spectrum of tales</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 21:34:28 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.mseri.me/tags/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Research Minutes</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/research-minutes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 21:34:28 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.mseri.me/research-minutes/</guid><description>Since September I am a member of the Young Academy Groningen. One of the nice perks of being part of such incredible group of people (yes, I still wonder how I got there :P) was the opportunity to take a short course on dealing with the media and to record my &amp;ldquo;research minutes&amp;rdquo;, a short, 2 minutes long, video to popularize my work.
The video was published on Twitter some time ago, and is now available on youtube.</description></item><item><title>A Micro Course on Sub-Riemannian Geometry</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/micro-course-on-sr-geometry/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 09:30:42 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.mseri.me/micro-course-on-sr-geometry/</guid><description>Last year I had the opportunity to give the first talk at the The Dutch Differential Topology &amp;amp; Geometry seminar (DDT&amp;amp;G). This was a 3 hour long event in which I had the chance to give a high-level introduction to sub-Riemannian geometry and present some interesting results and open questions partly related to my research.
In the first part of the seminar I introduced what are sub-Riemannian structures, where do they come from and what are some of the major properties and open questions, using some famous examples to drive the discussion.</description></item><item><title>Four Golden Lessons</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/four-golden-lessons/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 11:04:57 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.mseri.me/four-golden-lessons/</guid><description>The recent death of Steven Weinberg, winner of the Nobel prize in Physics and one of the most brilliant scientists of our times, made many people look back to his incredible production. In addition to some incredible eulogies, this has allowed a lot of little gems to resurface. Here I want to share one of them.
In 2003, Weinberg wrote a short note to PhD students in physics: &amp;ldquo;Four Golden Lessons&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Material from Hamiltonian Mechanics 2021</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/links-from-hm/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 00:15:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.mseri.me/links-from-hm/</guid><description>During the current incarnation of the course in Hamiltonian Mechanics I have collected some amount of material to share with the students. To avoid losing it in the guts of our teaching CMS, I leave it here for posterity, practically copy-pasting it without edits because I am really tired :D
The books on SpringerLinks linked below are accessible from our students for free via the university proxy but in general (unfortunately) not open access.</description></item><item><title>Lecture notes on Analysis on Manifolds</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/analysis-on-manifolds/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 13:17:25 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.mseri.me/analysis-on-manifolds/</guid><description>In the previous academic term I had the pleasure to teach Analysis on Manifolds, essentially an introduction to differential geometry for third year students.
In the course I tried to address the topic with the perspective that some of the students would be joining also my master course in Hamiltonian Mechanics later on next year. So many of the topics go in the direction of introducing the prerequisites for studying flows, symplectic geometry and sub-Riemannian geometry.</description></item><item><title>Steven Strogatz ask me anything video</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/steven-strogatz-ama/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 13:10:51 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.mseri.me/steven-strogatz-ama/</guid><description>This is a follow up from the previous post. I have stumbled upon a wonderful recent video by Steven Strogatz on Twitter which I believe could be extremely helpful for current and prospective PhD students in STEM, and for their advisors!
I think it is worth every minute of it:
Consider also listening to Strogatz' The Joy of x podcast, it gives a beautiful, humane and informative snapshot into what research and researchers are like.</description></item><item><title>On doing a PhD (in STEM)</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/on-doing-phd/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 10:45:35 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.mseri.me/on-doing-phd/</guid><description>I was asked a few times in the recent past if doing a PhD is worth the effort. Since then, I have been thinking of writing what I think on my blog but, as usual, I could never find the time for it. Not long ago, Jacopo Bertolotti shared his thoughts on the same matter in a nice twitter thread.
Since that really resonated with what I had to say, I&amp;rsquo;ll let him speak also for me and add a few more comments at the end.</description></item><item><title>Micro Course in Spectral Sub Riemannian Geometry</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/micro-course-ddtandg/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 22:38:21 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.mseri.me/micro-course-ddtandg/</guid><description>Recently, I have had the pleasure and honour to give a &amp;ldquo;micro&amp;rdquo; course on spectral sub-Riemannian geometry for the Dutch Differential Topology and Geometry seminar. Given the current global circumstances, the course was given via Zoom and the organizers and participants have been kind enough to have it recorded and published online.
You can access the recordings of the first and second lecture on the YouTube Channel of the DDT&amp;amp;G. The slides are also available (beware, they are 99Mb of handwritten pdf!</description></item><item><title>Lecture notes on Hamiltonian mechanics (update)</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/hamiltonian-mechanics-ams/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 22:00:21 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.mseri.me/hamiltonian-mechanics-ams/</guid><description>I have just released a small update to the Hamiltonian Mechanics lecture notes here. This contains some edits to improve the english and fix a few typos. The lecture notes have also been approved to appear in the AMS Open Math Notes, which seems to be a very nice initiative, full of very interesting and high quality content.</description></item><item><title>Lecture notes on Hamiltonian mechanics</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/lecture-notes-hamiltonian-mechanics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 15:20:19 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.mseri.me/lecture-notes-hamiltonian-mechanics/</guid><description>In the last academic term, I had the great pleasure to teach Hamiltonian Mechanics, an optional master course for mathematics and physics students. Even though the course was based on Arnold&amp;rsquo;s beautiful book, my plan for the course was to give a panoramic on the modern theory of integrable systems and perturbation theory. Of course, my grand plan, was way to optimistic. And between the time available, a bad flu and then the pandemic landing, we were able to do much less than what I hoped for.</description></item></channel></rss>