<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Popularization on A fractal spectrum of tales</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/tags/popularization/</link><description>Recent content in Popularization on A fractal spectrum of tales</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 17:32:08 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.mseri.me/tags/popularization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Man Who Saved Geometry</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/the-man-who-saved-geometry/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 17:32:08 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.mseri.me/the-man-who-saved-geometry/</guid><description>&lt;p>The other day I found an old file with links to interesting videos.
Some of them were no longer available, some I still have to check, but &lt;a href="https://vimeo.com/120725835">one caught my attention&lt;/a> and the other evening I decided to watch it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is a little documentary on the last conference of &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Harold_Scott_MacDonald_Coxeter">Donald Coexeter&lt;/a>, and I enjoed watching it very much. You can find it embedded below, and linked above. And while collecting links for this post I have also discovered &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20220102093914/https://www.math.toronto.edu/mpugh/Coxeter.pdf">a nice writeup&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Research Minutes</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/research-minutes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 21:34:28 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.mseri.me/research-minutes/</guid><description>&lt;p>Since September I am a member of the &lt;a href="https://www.rug.nl/news/2021/03/the-young-academy-groningen-welcomes-seven-new-members">Young Academy Groningen&lt;/a>.
One of the nice perks of being part of such incredible group of people (yes, I still wonder how I got there :P) was the opportunity to take a short course on dealing with the media and to record my &amp;ldquo;research minutes&amp;rdquo;, a short, 2 minutes long, video to popularize my work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The video was published on &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/YAGroningen/status/1441035218014687239">Twitter&lt;/a> some time ago, and is now available on youtube.
I hope you will enjoy it as much as I did enjoy recording it :)&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>