<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ghost on A fractal spectrum of tales</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/tags/ghost/</link><description>Recent content in Ghost on A fractal spectrum of tales</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2014 13:20:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.mseri.me/tags/ghost/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ghost 0.4.0 is out</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/ghost-0-4-0-is-out/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2014 13:20:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.mseri.me/ghost-0-4-0-is-out/</guid><description>&lt;p>and the ghost update script has been updated to mirror the changes in the update procedure. You can find it here: &lt;a href="https://gist.github.com/mseri/7059958">https://gist.github.com/mseri/7059958&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Updates for &lt;code>purity&lt;/code> to support all the new features are going to be released very soon.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As you can read from &lt;a href="https://blog.ghost.org/ghost-0-4/">the official announcement&lt;/a>, the new release of Ghost comes with a huge amount of features and updates:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Static pages&lt;/strong>. You can now toggle any post to be a &amp;ldquo;page&amp;rdquo; from within your post settings menu. This will remove it from your post feed. About / Contact / Terms galore!&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Unsaved changes notifications&lt;/strong>. We&amp;rsquo;ll now give you a heads up when you&amp;rsquo;re about to lose unsaved changes. So you can, you know, save.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Featured posts&lt;/strong>. You can now mark posts as featured, and style them accordingly from within your theme.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Sexy new loading bar&lt;/strong>. Always know when Ghost is doing something, a little blue bar crawls across the screen to let you know!&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Quick edit post urls&lt;/strong>. You can now slap /edit/ on the end of any post URL and, boom, you&amp;rsquo;re editing it.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Date based permalink support&lt;/strong>. If you like that kind of thing.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>SSL support and a more secure password reset process&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Over 100 bugfixes and minor improvements!&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/TryGhost/Ghost/wiki/Release-Notes:-0.4.0">Much, much more&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Don&amp;rsquo;t waste time. Update your ghost!!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A great workaround for targeting links in Ghost</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/a-great-workaround-for-targeting-links-in-ghost/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2013 15:53:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.mseri.me/a-great-workaround-for-targeting-links-in-ghost/</guid><description>&lt;p>When I am reading something, I hate to click on some link (that I will supposedly read later) and be redirected to the new page. I&amp;rsquo;d rather prefer the links to open in background in a new tab.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You may say that it is enough to click while pressing Command or Control and the page will be opened in a background tab, but it&amp;rsquo;s not the same. What if I accidentally click for example?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Update script explained</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/update-script-explained/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2013 14:02:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.mseri.me/update-script-explained/</guid><description>&lt;p>I am going to proceed step by step through the code of the script that I have &lt;a href="https://www.mseri.me/a-simple-script-to-update-ghost/">posted few days ago&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I purposedly updated the script to be a bit more general and flexible (but not too much). At the end of the file I explain how to run it. You should &lt;a href="https://docs.ghost.org/installation/upgrading/">make a backup&lt;/a> before doing the update (the simplest way is probably running &lt;code>tar czf backup.tar.gz YOUR_GHOST_FOLDER&lt;/code>). Be careful that there is no warranty with this script and I will not take any responsibility for claims or damages consequent to the use of it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A simple script to update ghost</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/a-simple-script-to-update-ghost/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2013 19:04:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.mseri.me/a-simple-script-to-update-ghost/</guid><description>&lt;p>You can update your ghost engine in many different ways, two for all by hand or by using git.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am personally using a very basic bash script. If you need a semiauthomatic way to run the update, you can just &lt;a href="https://gist.github.com/mseri/7059958">copy/download it from gist&lt;/a> and adapt to your needs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think it is simple enough to require no explanation.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --></description></item><item><title>nginx, ghost 0.3.3 and modsecurity</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/nginx-ghost-0-3-3-and-modsecurity/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2013 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.mseri.me/nginx-ghost-0-3-3-and-modsecurity/</guid><description>&lt;p>In my previous post, &lt;a href="https://www.mseri.me/ghost-on-amazon-ec2-without-using-sudo/">Ghost on Amazon EC2 without using sudo&lt;/a>, I was proposing some way of running ghost without having to use sudo and with at least a minimal eye on security.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you have followed one of the guides that I suggested, namely &lt;a href="https://blog.igbuend.com/dude-looks-like-a-ghost/">Dude Looks Like a Ghost&lt;/a>, or you have installed your own &lt;a href="https://www.modsecurity.org">modsecurity&lt;/a> configuration you should have received a big page announcing an &lt;strong>Error 403&lt;/strong> right after the update of your ghost to version &lt;em>0.3.3&lt;/em>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ghiOStSeven</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/ghiostseven/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2013 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.mseri.me/ghiostseven/</guid><description>&lt;p>Here we go. On &lt;a href="https://github.com/mseri/ghiosSeven">github&lt;/a> is finally available a new responsive ghost theme inspired by iOS7 look.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is still a very preliminary version, a cleaning of the stylesheet and some additional tweaks are in progress.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the next few days I will add a style for forms elements to look like they do in iOS7 and the social/rss icons on the boottom bar, aligned right.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the meanwhile you can play with it (and may be pull some update for merging) going to &lt;a href="https://github.com/mseri/ghiosSeven">github.com/mseri/ghiosSeven&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ghost up and running on Amazon EC2</title><link>https://www.mseri.me/ghost-up-and-running-on-amazon-ec2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2013 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.mseri.me/ghost-up-and-running-on-amazon-ec2/</guid><description>&lt;p>I had my free Amazon EC2 instance waiting for this moment since &lt;a href="https://github.com/mseri/pplofthesoil">my last use of it&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I spent my few free hours setting up a decent (I hope) &lt;a href="https://github.com/mseri/purity">theme&lt;/a> for &lt;a href="https://ghost.org">Ghost&lt;/a>, and reading around what to do and what not to do to have it up and running. My main reference was the nice blog post &lt;a href="https://www.howtoinstallghost.com/how-to-setup-an-amazon-ec2-instance-to-host-ghost-for-free/">How to set up an Amazon EC2 instance to host ghost for free&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I followed more or less all the steps suggested in the guide but there was still something missing: I wanted my Ghost blog to be running even when I am not logged in the EC2 instance.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>